Guide to the Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals M-Z, Series II
  - Sherrill, Edwin Jenner and Sarah Foote
    - Photographs; Sarah Foote Sherrill; House at Eaton, Canada; Portrait of the Rev. Joseph Raphael Andrus, missionary to Sierra Leone (uncle of EJS) (Box 306)
  - Shirk, Allen and Elsie
    The Shirks were Mennonite missionaries stationed in India.
    - Fourteen letters written to family membersy by the Shirks, primarily from Latehar, Palamau District, Bihar, describe their mission work and family matters., 1951-1956 (Box 303, Folder 28)
  - Simpson, Carrie
    Carrie Simpson and her husband Edwin were American Presbyterian missionaries in Western India.
    - Letter from Simpson describes her day, written from "Desolate Lodge" to her husband who is at Travellers Bungalow in Kohlapur., 1910 (Box 303, Folder 29)
  - Simpson, W.
    W. Simpson was a missionary in India, serving under the Wesleyan Mission.
    - Letter to W. Simpson from the Christian Congregation of Chitaldroog, written in gratitude for his work as he begins his furlough. Large format inscribed letter signed by eight members of the congregation., 1891 (Box 303, Folder 30)
  - Sinclair, John H.
    ohn Sinclair was a Presbyterian missionary in Latin America and mission board secretary of the United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. (1960-1973). This collection contains resource files collected by Sinclair, primarily related to mission, church, and ecumenical groups in Latin America. His personal papers will be with the Presbyterian Historical Society.
    - Collected papers: Borges dos Santos Junior, Jose, "Era Christo Comunista?"(n.d.); Casals, Jose: "Hymns of Commitment: Ethical and Theological Values"; Kroehler, Lois: "Salvador Allende" (1975,1976); Cotto, Augusto: "We Need Dialogue Between Cuba and the Rest of the Continent" (1978); Escobar, Samuel: "Future Trends" (1987); Glidden, Earl: "Marxism – Science or Superstition" (1984); Goff, James E.: "The Evangelical Confederation of Colombia" (1962); Goff, James E.: "U.S. Aid to Colombia Schools Has it Promoted Democracy? (1964 ), 1962-1987, n.d. (Box 393, Folder 1)
    - Collected papers: Guerra, Israel Batista: "The Christian-Marxist Encounter in Cuba" (1978); Gutierrez, Gustavo: "Praxis of Liberation and the Christian Faith" (1973); Hromadka, Josef: "O Serico da Teologia" (1970); Hromadka, J. L.: "Peace on Earth" (1961); Jabusch, Willard F. "Protestants in Latin America" (1960), 1960-1978 (Box 393, Folder 2)
    - Collected papers: Kreps, George and Marty:" Review and Recommendation of the Church of the Brethren Missionary Activities In Ecuador", 1991 (Box 393, Folder 3)
    - Collected papers: Langella, Gaspar B.: "The Caribbean Context of the Experience of the Cuban Church" (1979); Molena Uriel, et al.: "Christian Fidelity in the Revolutionary Process of Nicaragua" (1981 ); Nebelsick, Harold P.: "Report from Germany"(1963); Nosso, Olai: "Santificado Seja o Teu Nome" (n.d.); O'Leary de Macias, Geraldine: "Only Another Tyranny" (1983), 1963-1983, n.d. (Box 393, Folder 4)
    - Collected papers: Padilla, Fernando Villalobos: "?Que Creen los Comunista?" (1961); Reyburn, William D. and Marie F.: "Picalqui: Retrospect and Prospect" (1955); Ruiz, Bishop Samuel: "The Rebellion of the Excluded" (1994), 1955-1994, n.d. (Box 393, Folder 5)
    - Collected papers: Sinclair, John H.: "Conversation With Roman Catholics and the Latin American Churches", 1961-1964 (Box 393, Folder 6)
    - Collected papers: Smith, Dennis A.: "Pistas Polemicas para una Pastoral de Fin de Melenio" (1983); Stoll, David: "Wycliffe Bible Translators: Not Telling The Whole Truth" (1983); Toalombo, Mariano, et al., Proyecto Autofinanciamiento de Vivienda para Indigenas Migrantes en Quito" (1992), 1983-1992 (Box 393, Folder 7)
    - Related to organizations and events: "Que es Cehila?" (1976?); II Conferencia General – Hostoria de la Iglesia en America Latina y el Caribe: 1945-1995" (1995) Poster for above conference; Poster for "Simposio – Protestantismo y Politica en America; Entre la Sociedad Civil y el Estado" (1994), 1976-1995 (Box 393, Folder 8)
    - CEHILA Boletin: 1973; 1975 Mar, Sep, Oct; 1976 Jun; 1977 Feb, Jun; 1978 Mar, Sep; 1979 Jan, Jun, Oct; 1980 Mar; 1944 Jan-Apr; 1994 May-Aug, 1973-1994 (Box 393, Folder 9-12)
      The Comision de Estudios de Historia de la Iglesia en America Latina (CEHILA) was an ecumenical effort in the 1970s- 1990s chaired by Enrique Dussel (Mexico) to write a history of the Christian church in Latin America. There were about ten volumes written by Roman Catholic and Protestant historians
    - Student papers: Benjamin, Audrey: "Isabelle Thoburn – Woman of Vision and Faith"; Benjamin, Audrey, "An Overview of Kenya and Study of a Religious Community"; Dahl, Dan: "Roland Allen - A Person in Tune With and Ahead of his Time"; Vorderbruggen, Cheri: "Conflict of the Christian Church in Costa Rica"; Ward, Susan: "John G. Paton 19th Century Missionary to the New Hebrides", 1980 (Box 393, Folder 13)
      From course taught by Sinclair at Macalester College: "The Third World Church in Historical Perspective"
    - Report: Shafer, Heinrich: "Studies from the World Alliance of Reformed Churches", 1988 (Box 393, Folder 14)
    - Nueva Lectura de Centro America: Entrevista de Gary Campbell a diez dirigentes de la Iglesia Evangelica Nacional Presbiteriana de Guatemala: with Roberto Lopez Velasquez, Sr. Arnulfo Archila, Rev, Candido Pensamiento, Sr. Cesar Ajanel, Sr. Francisco Perez, Rev. Jose Romero, Sr. Antonio Otzoy, Sra. Sonia de Gomez, Daniel Tellez, Elfego de Leon, Raquel Lausch, David Winters, Rev. Marco Antonio Rodriquez Perez, Judith Castaneda, Rafael Escobar, Nancy Rosas, 1994 (Box 394, Folder 1)
    - Nueva Lectura de Centro America: Benjamin Cortes, Pablo Cruz, Violeta Rocha, Gustavo Parajon, Prof. Gilberto Aguirre, P.Uriel Mollna, Rafael Valdez, Zoraida Soza, Rosa Mercado, Nan McCurdy, Rev. Miguel Angel Casco, Rev. Mendelson Davila, Rev. Ruben Alvarez, Rev. Carlos Villagra, 1994 (Box 394, Folder 2)
    - Collected essays and reports: Huck, Eugene R. and Moseley, Edward H.: "Militarists, Merchants, and Missionaries" (1970 ); Enns, Arno: "Man, Milieu and Mission in Argentina" (1971); Wagner, C. Peter: "The Protestant Movement in Bolivia" (1970); Vingren, Ivar: "Pionjarens dagbok" (1968); Hageman, Alice L.and Wheaton, Philip E.: "Religion in Cuba Today" (1971); DeCordoba, Pedro: "Christian Doctrine for the Instruction and Information of the Indians" (1970); Enyart, Paul C: "Friends in Central America" (1970); Melville, Thomas and Marjorie: "Whose Heaven, Whose Earth" (1972); Haiti – Status of Christianity (1972); Baumgartner, Jacob: "Mission Und Liturgtie in Mexico" (1972; Kessel, John L.: "Mission of Sorrows: Jesuit Guevari and the Pimas 1691-1767" (1970); Ravicz, Marilyn Ekdahl: "Early Colonial Religious Drama in Mexico from Tzompantila to Golgotha" (1970); Martin, Luis: "The Intellectual Conquest of Peru, The Jesuit College of San Pablo 1568-1767"(1968); Chang, Lit-Sen: "Strategy of Missions in the Orient Christian Impact on the Pagan World" (1970); Goff, James: "A Critical Review of Latin American Church Growth (1970); Church Growth Bulletin: 1964; Statement WCC Department of Missionary Studies Iberville, Quebec ((1963); Report – The Committee on Church Growth; Outline: Research Project in Latin America; Institute of Church Growth: Response from Donald McGavran ( 1964); Memorandum of Discussion – Church Growth as Guide for Mission Policy (1963);Moraes, Benjamin: "Analysis: A Brazilian Reacts to McGavran" (1965 ); McGavran, Donald A.: "Social Justices and Evangelism" (1965), 1963-1972 (Box 394, Folder 3)
    - Collected essays and reports: Editorial – Reflexion Teologica; Reunion – English Language Publication, 1995 (Box 394, Folder 4)
    - Collected essays and reports: Guatemala: Relazione Annua Dell'Ufficio Legale; N.Y. State Ecclesiastical Court Digest (1964,1965), 1961-1965 (Box 394, Folder 5,6)
    - Re. Institute on Religion and Democracy: Hunter, Miguel Bolanos: "Briefing Paper - Subversion of the Church in Nicaragua" (1983); Ledeen, Michael A. "The Grenada Documents: Archive of Church Subversion" (1984); Newsletter – Institute on Religion and Democracy (1984); Newsletter – Religion and Democracy (1983); IRD Report – "Church Support for Pro-Sandinista Network" (1984) ;Institute on Religion and Democracy Statement of Purpose ( 1985), 1983-1985 (Box 394, Folder 6)
      The Institute on Religion and Democracy was a conservative group of lay people, primarily in the Presbyterian churches, which opposed the Sandinista revolutino in Nicaragua.
    - Re: All Christian Peace Assembly in Prague, 1961 (Box 394, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Peace Corps to M. V. Little; M. V. Little to/from Senator Wayne Morse (re. U. S Government Aid to Colombian Education);; James E. Goff to John C. Smith (re. Latin American Church Growth); Edmund W. Mobb, Michael Novak and Richard J. Neuhaus to "Friend" (circulating petition – Defend Churches of Nicaragua); George P. Morgan to Edmunt W. Robb (response to petition letter.), 1961-1984 (Box 394, Folder 8)
    - Book reviews: primarily by John Sinclair, in Bulletin of the Scottish Institute of Missionary Studies, 1964-1971 (Box 394, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous documents: Consejo Episcopal Latinoamericano - CELAM (1975); Re. Indigenous People in Ecuador (n.d.); Letter from Jose Jacinto Guaman to John Sinclair - re. Ecuador (1992); OMSC – Emerging Models of Christian Missions – Notice of Special Consultation ( 1976); IDOC Documentation Participation Project: Mozambique: The Church and Socialist Revolution Nambia: (1976); The "Christians for Socialism" Movement Religion in Communist Dominated Areas (1970); Facts for Action – the Threat of the Radical ReligiousRight (1994); Report on a Visit to Washington, D. C. re. Panama; Task Force on Latin America – Report on Current Activities and Upcoming Decisions (1994); Call to the World – World Conference in Solidarity with Cuba ( 1994 ); Report on Serpaj Asamblea, Phil McManus (199?); "ONIS Priest Movement – Out of Hunger into the Fight - Peru" (1978), 1970-1994 (Box 394, Folder 10)
    - CEHILA papers (Box 394, Folder 11)
    - "Footnotes on the Beginnings of the Evangelical Movement in Guatemala" by E. M. Haymaker, 1946 (Box 451, Folder 1)
    - Memoir of Howard Yoder, Methodist missionary in Peru and Bolivia 1929-1954, later Executive Secretary of the Committee on Cooperation in Latin America, NCCUSA, 1983 (Box 451, Folder 2)
    - Materials related to 80th Anniversary of the 1929 Hispano-American Evangelical Congress of Havana, including paper prepared by Sinclair for Edinburgh 2010 gathering, 2009-2010 (Box 451, Folder 3)
    - "The Dawn of Ecumenism in Latin America: Robert E. Speer, Presbyterians, and the Panama Conference of 1916": article by John H. Sinclair and Arturo Piedra Solano, with background material, 1999, no date (Box 451, Folder 4)
    - "El Evangelio en Una Edad Revolucionaria: The United Andean Indian Mission in Ecuador, 1945-1967" by Devin Caughey (Yale senior essay) and related correspondence, 2004 (Box 451, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous clippings and brochures re. Latin America (Box 451, Folder 6)
    - Biographical and autobiographical writings related to Alexander M. Allan, Presbyterian missionary in Colombia 1910-1946. (Box 282, Folder 19-20)
  - Singh, Hajom Kissor
    Singh was a Unitarian minister in India
    - Handwritten letter addressed to Miss L.L. Clarke of Boston thanks her for books received and describes Unitarian work in India, 1894 (Box 456, Folder 3)
  - Singh, Sadhu Sundar
    Sundar Singh was born into an important landowning Sikh family in Patiala State in northern India in 1889. He was converted to Christianity and was baptized in 1905. Rejected by his family, he became a Christian missionary traveling widely in India as well as throughout the world.
    - Three bound typescript volumes labeled III, IV, V. The volumes contain extracts from the Nur Afshan newspaper, Ludhiana, regarding the work of Sundar Singh (1912-1928). (Box 382, Folder 1)
  - Sirlinger, Eugene
    Father Eugène Sirlinger was stationed at Shendam Mission, which was the first Roman Catholic Mission north of the rivers Niger and Benue in Nigeria. Sirlinger arrived at the mission in 1913.
    - Photograph album documenting mission activity in northern Nigeria (digital versions available), 1923 (Box 449, Folder 2)
    - Loose photographs, two letters, one from Fr. Sirlinger to "Mary", newspaper clipping about bridge in Nigeria, 1933-1935, no date (Box 449, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Gordon and Laura
    The Smiths were missionaries in Vietnam, serving under the Worldwide Evangelization Crusade.
    - Circular letter describing their work in Danang, Vietnam, 1963 (Box 282, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Helen
    Identified by vendor as Methodist missionary in India.
    - Handwritten diary of Helen Smith (as identified by vendor) describes her life and work at a Methodist Mission school in India. One photo and some notes., 1930 (Box 303, Folder 31)
  - Smith, W. A.
    - Manuscript sermon, 1912 Jan 7 (Box 282, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Wilmina Rowland
    M. A. in Religious Education from Yale 1937; served Presbyterian Board of Christian Education, Student Volunteer Movement, World Student Service Fund, Mississippi Delta Ministry; ordained as Presbyterian minister 1957, served Indian Hill Presbyterian Church.
    - Student Volunteer Movement (SVM): "Diary of a Travelling Secretary", 1933-1934 (Box 336, Folder 1-2)
    - SVM: Correspondence, publicity brochure, 1933-1966 (Box 336, Folder 3)
    - SVM: Material related to 12th Quadrennial Convention, Indianapolis, 1935-1936 (Box 336, Folder 4)
    - SVM: Report of trip to colleges throughout U.S., 1936 Feb-Apr (Box 336, Folder 5)
    - SVM: "A Primer of Christian Missions" by Wilmina Rowland in collaboratin with a Committee of the Ninth General Council of the Student Volunteer Movement (study manual), 1934 (Box 336, Folder 6)
    - World Student Service Fund (WSSF) / European Student Relief Fund: Circular letters from Europe, 1945 Apr - 1947 Apr (Box 336, Folder 7)
    - WSSF: Reports/writings of WR re. European student relief, 1945-1947 (Box 336, Folder 8)
    - WSSF: "Reminiscences of Wilmina Rowland of her years with the World Student Service Fund (1941-1944) and with World Student Relief (1945-1947), 1979 (Box 336, Folder 9)
    - WSSF: Photographs from trips to Europe, 1945-1946 (Box 336, Folder 10)
    - Reminiscences re. World Student Relief by Ruth Young, 1979 (Box 336, Folder 11)
    - Re. ordination, service at Indian Hill Presbyterian Church, 1957-1959 (Box 336, Folder 12)
    - Mississippi Delta Ministry (civil rights ministry of National Council of Churches): Report letters by WR, 1964 Oct - 1965 Jan (Box 336, Folder 13)
    - Mississippi Delta Ministry: Weekly reports, 1964 Oct - 1965 Jan (Box 336, Folder 14)
    - Mississippi Delta Ministry: Articles, editorial, speech by WR, 1964-1965 (Box 336, Folder 15)
    - Presbyterian Board of Christian Education: correspondence, writings, collected material, 1960-1973 (Box 336, Folder 16)
    - Writings of WR, n.d. (Box 336, Folder 17)
    - Prayer delivered in U.S. Senate, 1971 Jul 8 (Box 336, Folder 18)
    - Marriage to H. Maxcy Smith, 1973 (Box 336, Folder 19)
    - Reminiscences re. Student Christian Movement, 1975 (Box 336, Folder 20)
    - Biographical documentation, 1937-1972 (Box 336, Folder 21-23)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1993 (Box 336, Folder 24)
    - Collected material re. Protestant leaders, incl. Robert Mackie, Eugene Carson Blake, 1976-1985 (Box 336, Folder 25)
  - Spangenberg, Bradford
    Yale Divinity School graduate, Class of 1961. He was a Professor of History at Temple University and an active clergyman of the Susquehanna Conference of the United Methodist Church.
    These papers consist of syllabi, notes, papers from courses taken by Spangenberg at Yale Divinity School 1958-1961.
    - American Higher Education and Religion - Prof. Dirks, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - American Religious Conservatism - Prof. Ahlstrom, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Church History, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Church and the Ministry, 1958-1959 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - College Teaching of Religion - Prof. Dirks, 1960-1961 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Comparative Religion - Prof. Hein, 1959-1960 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Comparative Religion - Prof. Hein, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Methodist Polity, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Old Testament Interpretation - Prof. Childs, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Old Testament Interpretation - Prof. Childs, 1958-1959 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Religion and Music - Prof. Krigbaum, 1961 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Systematic Theology Seminar: The Doctrine of God - Prof. Lindbeck, 1960 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - YDS Student Directories 1958-1959, 1959-1960, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Spaulding family
    Mary Amanda Spaulding Parker Palmer served as secretary for the Chelmsford (Massachusetts) Female Sewing Society, which did charitable work for the American Baptist Mission to the Bassa tribe in Liberia, Africa. Zebulon Spaulding (1779-1854) was the father of Mary Amanda.
    - Four annual reports of the Chelmsford Female Sewing Society, written by Amanda Spaulding, include information about the African mission work being support by the Society, 1841-1844 (Box 323, Folder 5)
    - Handwritten copy of letter to Mrs. Solomon Parker Spaulding from William G. Crocker missionary to Liberia; extract of letter from Crocker to Dr. Bolles, 1840 (Box 323, Folder 6)
    - Account book of Zebulon Spaulding of Carlisle, MA provides family information in addition to record of activities and accounts, 1799-1849 (Box 323, Folder 7)
  - Spear, Frederick Gordon
    British medical doctor who served at a mission hospital in Yakusu, Belgian Congo under the the Baptist Missionary Society. He received his medical degree in 1919 and then studied tropical medicine before going to the Congo. After his return to England in 1923 he worked at Strangeways Laboratory in Cambridge.
    - Manuscript journal written by F. Gordon Spear during his work as a medical missionary in the Belgian Congo (700 pp.), 1922-1923 (Box 422, Folder 1)
    - Excerpts from Spear's journal printed in the "Yalemba Monthly Letter" of the Baptist Missionary Society, 1923 Nov 10 (Box 422, Folder 2)
  - Spencer, Robert Steward
    Spencer was a Methodist missionary in Japan.
    - Two issues of mimeographed "Fukuoka News Letter" described the work of Spencer and his wife Evelyn in Fukuoka, Japan, 1934 (Box 303, Folder 32)
  - Starr, Edward Comfort
    Starr was pastor of the Wethersfield Avenue Church in Hartford, Connecticut.
    - Handwritten discourse delivered in Wethersfield Avenue Church, Hartford, related to history of the church, 1876 July 9 (Box 303, Folder 36)
  - Stanford, Arthur Willis
    1859 Jan 10 Born in Lowell, Massachusetts; 1882 B.A., Amherst; 1885 B.D., Yale; 1886-1920 Missionary to Japan, A.B.C.F.M. - Kyoto, Kobe, Matsuyama. Editor of Mission News; 1886-1895 Professor of Old Testament Literature and Exegesis, Doshisha University;1921 Died.
    - Correspondence, incl. To AWS from student, Y. Yoshikama (1890 Jun 17); To S. Lyons, U.S. Consul from I. Hirata (copy) (1902 Jul 10); To AWS from Wm. G. Seiple with enclosures (1919 Oct 6, 29); (copies of inscriptions near images of Jizo); To AWS from Arthur W. Hummel (1920 May 23); To AWS from Harold Cooper (1920 Jul 6); Fragment of letter from Alice Cary (n.d.) (Box 292)
    - Notes re. Japanese subjects (Box 292)
    - Published writings by AWS: Introduction to the Psalms (1891); "Buddhism's Fundamental Teaching" in Mission News (1920 Feb 16);"Yakushi Nyorai" in Mission News (1920 Jul 15) (Box 292)
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings re. Japanese subjects, 1905-1920, n.d. (Box 292)
    - Japanese language material; Photographs (Box 292)
  - Stern, Israel
    - Manuscript entitled "A Defense of the Master Jesus of Nazareth", written by Stern, 135 pp., 1932 (Box 112)
  - Stevens, George Barker
    1854 - Born; 1877 - B.A. University of Rochester; 1880 - B.D. Yale; 1883 - Ph.D. Syracuse University; 1886 - D.D. University of Jena; 1886-1895 - Buckingham Professor of New Testament Criticism and Interpretation, Yale; 1895-1906 - Dwight Professor of Systematic Theology, Yale; 1906 - Died.
    - Sermons: Date and place preached are noted on the sermons, 1879-1906 (Box 108)
    - Article: "Bushnell, Ritschl, and Sabatier: A Comparison and an Estimate" (Box 108)
    - Bound volume of notes by student Karl Owen Thompson from lectures by Stevens: "Theism. Systematic Theology. Science of Christian Faith", ca. 1905-1907 (Box 386, Folder 15)
  - Stevenson, John Ogilvie
    Born in Scotland, 1841, Stevenson came to the America in 1863 by way of Canada. Following a period in Minnesota he served under the American Missionary Assoociation in Texas, teaching freed slaves, including as principal of Barnes Institute in Galveston. In 1872 he entered Yale Divinity School and received a B.D. in 1875. He served Congregational churches in Ellsworth, Connecticut (1875-1879), Shenandoah, Iowa (1880-1885) and Waterloo, Iowa (1896-1898). Later in life he lost his voice but continued to communicate via writing. He was the editor of the Woman's Standard, a suffragist newspaper, and wrote editorials for the Waterloo Courier. He died in 1912. For more detailed biographical information see a statement by his great granddaughter Flora Beach Burlingame in the first folder of the collection.
    - Sermons: From texts in Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Joshua, Judges, Samuel, Kings, Isaiah, 1870s-1890s (Box 388, Folder 1-7)
    - Sermons: From texts in Ecclesiastes, Job, Psalms, Ezekiel, Daniel, Hosea, Joel, Jonah, Zephaniah, Malachi, Matthew, Mark, Luke, John, 1870s-1890s (Box 389, Folder 1-6)
    - Sermons: From texts in Acts, Romans, Corinthians, Ephesians, Timothy, Titus, James, Peter, I John, Revelation, 1870s-1890s (Box 390, Folder 1-6)
    - Sermons series on Balaam, David, Jonah, 1870s-1890s (Box 391, Folder 1-2)
    - Talks and articles: on theologians and authors, 1880s (Box 391, Folder 3-4)
    - Talks and articles: including on "Gaelic Christianity", "Pioneering", "Modern Theological and Religious Thought", "Calvinism – What is it?", "Driftwood", "Old Glory", "Independence Day", "The Worlds Fair", "That Boy's Sister", "Memorial (General Grant)", "Garfield's Assassination", "The Native American"," The Relation of Woman's Suffrage to the Vital Problems of Society", "The Folks at Home (Reunion)", 1880s-1890s (Box 391, Folder 5)
    - Talks and articles: including on "The Story of Liberty", "Closing Days of Christian Progress", "Commencement", "Christian Hash", "The Temperance Outlook", "Wages" (article, newspaper), "A Unique Catechism" (news article), "Sunday School Missionary" (article), "Religion of Character Christian Knowledge", "Open Communion", "The Ascension of Christ", "Signs of the Times (A Thesis)", "Government Prophecy", "The Andover Controversy", "Conditional Import", "Wesleyanism as a Logical and Practical System", 1880s-1890s (Box 391, Folder 6)
    - Editorials: including on "Moral Wealth", "Government", "A Day Dream", "Gehenna", "Match Making", "The Bible", "Immortality", "Dress", "Moral Freedom", "Savonarola", "Punishment", "Seeing Things","Modern Vehicles", "Recreation", "Does Death End All?", "The Melting Pot", "Red Blood", "Holiness", 1880s-1890s (Box 392, Folder 1)
  - Stewart, Jennie F.
    Stewart (1858-1894) was appointed a missionary to Prome, Burma [Myanmar] from the First Baptist Church in Brockton, Massachusetts.